I'm here with Timo from Arvato.
我旁边的这位是来自 Arvato 的 Timo
You saw him in the first term of this program.
你在纳米学位的第一学期就见过他了
But you're back again for another project where we're working with the same data,
但这次你带来的项目跟上一次不同 虽然数据是一样的
but we left a lot of the complexity this time,
这次的项目比起上次的项目
that we removed the first time.
难度上会增加很多
Can you talk about the third data set that's introduced as well
你可以给我们讲讲这次新加入的第三个数据集 以及
as what's the ending goal that Arvato uses this data for?
Arvato 用这些数据想要最终达成的目标吗？
Sure. Firstly, welcome back and thank you for working on another project with our data.
当然 首先 欢迎回来 非常荣幸你们能使用我们的数据做项目
I hope you liked the initial one.
希望你喜欢
Now, we're introducing a third data set that you can use to actually evaluate your model,
现在 我们新加入了第三个数据集 让你可以评估你的模型
and test your recommendations you would be giving to our client with that model.
并用这个模型来测试我们给顾客发出的推荐是否有效
The project you have been working on is a real-life project.
这个项目场景是非常真实的
It's a project you would be working on as a data scientist at Bertelsmann Arvato.
如果你在 Bertelsmann Arvato 工作的话 你就会面对这样的问题
We have similar projects like this,
以及一些其他类似的业务场景
where you would be analyzing attributes,
你要分析用户属性
customers, for example, to recommend credit scores.
给顾客推荐比如说奖励积分等等
We're looking at several of these attributes you have been working
我们会关注几个顾客的指标
on to identify payment behavior,
你可以用这些指标来判断顾客的行为
predict payment behavior, recommend credit scores, calculate credit scores.
预测顾客的行为 推荐奖励积分 计算奖励积分
Can you talk a little bit about what you
你可以从商业角度再讲讲
want as an ending goal from a business perspective?
你希望学员能从项目中收获什么吗？
So, this whole new third data set that's come into play,
其实 这就是我们新加入第三个数据集的原因
now opens up a world of different questions and how we might be able to answer them.
你可以提出更多可能的问题 以及你如何进行解决
Absolutely. The underlying business question or the kind of problem statement is,
对从商业角度 最基本的问题就是
"How can our client,
"如何让我们的客户
the mail-order company acquire new clients more efficiently?"
一个邮购公司 更高效地获得新客户？"
What we're asking you to do is essentially,
你所要做的一切都应该围绕这个问题
you have the attributes and the demographic information of the existing clients,
你有既有用户的一些属性和人口统计数据
we would like you to analyze the attributes of these existing clients,
我们希望你分析这些既有用户有哪些特征
match them against a second,
将它们和第二个数据集做匹配
the bigger data set that includes attributes for people in Germany,
第二个数据集更大 包括的是德国人口的一些属性和人口统计数据
and essentially figure out which people in Germany are
然后找出德国的哪些人
most likely new customers for our client,
更可能成为该邮购公司的新客户
the mail-order company selling organic products.
这个邮购公司卖的是有机产品
From our kind of view,
从我们的角度出发
it's a real-life project.
这是一个现实场景下的项目
So essntially, what it has to do is increase
所以 本质上 要做的是提高
efficiency in the customer acquisition process.
客户获取效率
So, instead of the mail order company reaching out to all people
我们不可能让邮寄公司把广告发给每个德国人
in Germany and targeting them with a marketing campaign,
告诉他们参加这个邮寄活动
we would just then be reaching out to
我们只需要让他们联系那些
the people we identified as becoming most likely new customers,
最可能成为他们新客户的人群
and then do targeted advertising. That what it is.
然后定向地发送广告就是这样
Great. Right now, they have a culture where they make
很棒 这个公司的企业文化是
decisions based on past experiences,
基于过去的经验或直觉来做决策
intuition, and a lot of that is okay.
大多数情况下也是可行的
But if they can infuse those decisions by also backing them up with data,
但是如果能够结合一些数据
or even showing like,
来做出决策
we can go even further with this decision in x direction or y direction,
我们就能确保业务能通过更好的决策来发展地更好
that's where you guys come in. Is that true?
数据科学家就是承担了这样的一种角色 我说的对吗？
Absolutely. That's what we're doing.
对这正是我们在做的
The mission of our engagement is make decisions based on data instead of gut feel.
我们的目标就是基于数据而不是直觉和观感做决定
Of course, we are dealing with senior finance managers,
当然 我们面对的是很多高级的基金经理人
and they do have a lot of experience,
他们有丰富的经验
but our client is really conscious that they are using data points,
但是他们还是不习惯于基于数据做出决策
So, we would like to have them use more reports,
所以我们希望他们能做出改变
use reports more often,
多看看数据报告
request more reports, and actually use the data we are providing.
多使用数据报告来帮助业务决策
Timo, thanks so much for some insights into the data set.
Timo 感谢分享数据集的背景知识和你的观点
Sure. Thank you very much for participating in this project.
不客气 也感谢你能选择这个项目
I hope you find it insightful.
希望它让你有所收获
As I mentioned, it's data we're using.
我之前提到过 我们用到的数据
It's a real data science project.
完全来自真实的场景
So, thank you very much for that.
祝你顺利